A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 6262-9286 FA739C
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Report of consulting visit to Uruguay and Argentina, April 30-May 7, 1966 (Reports 008821) (Box 370)
  Education -- Paraguay; Education -- Uruguay; Technical education -- Paraguay; Technical education -- Uruguay; Teachers -- Training of -- Paraguay; Teachers -- Training of -- Uruguay; King, Richard G., 1922-; Ford Foundation. Vice President; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Report of my trip to Argentina, March 15 to May 1 (Reports 008822), 1969 (Box 370)
  Soils -- Research -- Argentina; Kohnke, Helmut, 1901-1991; National University of the South (Argentina) Soil Science Institute
- National University of the South, Bahia Blanca, Argentina (Reports 008823), 1968 (Box 370)
  Agronomy -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Argentina -- Curricula; Agriculture -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Argentina; Universities and colleges -- Argentina; Education, Higher -- Argentina; Krider, J. L. (Jake Luther), 1913-; Universidad Nacional del Sur. Departamento de Agronomía
- Reflection on "Cultural activities" memos (Reports 008824), 1968 (Box 371)
  Cultural property -- Protection -- Latin America; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Institute of Statistics, Institute of Technology, PASS (Reports 008825), 1966 (Box 371)
  PASS Argentine social security system; Institute of Statistics and Institute of Technology; Argentina -- Economic conditions; Argentina -- Social conditions; Levine, Arnold; PASS Argentine social security system; Institute of Statistics and Institute of Technology
- Latin American Postgradute Training Program (Reports 008826), 1966 (Box 371)
  Education, Higher -- Latin America; Universities and colleges -- Latin America -- Graduate work; Lloyd, Charles W.
- Review of the training program in Santiago, Chile, November 17-23 (Reports 008827), 1967 (Box 371)
  Population research -- Chile; Human reproduction -- Study and teaching -- Chile; Population assistance -- Chile; Birth control -- Chile; Lloyd, Charles W.; Ford Foundation. Latin America and Caribbean
- Observations made during April 1967 in Argentina, Santiago de Chile, Lima and Caracas (Reports 008828) (Box 371)
  Scientists -- Latin America; Cotton, F. Albert (Frank Albert), 1930-2007; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Program development trends that cause increased demand for management services (Reports 008829), 1967 (Box 371)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management; Endowments -- Evaluation; Technical assistance; Mayer, Robert A. (Robert Anthony)
- Delegated-authority projects: guidelines (Reports 008830), 1972 (Box 371)
  Delegated-authority projects; Guidelines -- Delegated-authority projects; Ford Foundation
- Meeting November 23, 1971: (4 issue papers) (Reports 008831) (Box 371)
  Memorandum to Task Force on Financial Accounting and Reporting.
  Financial accounting and reporting; Administrative expense; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management; Goodyear, F. R. D. (Francis Richard David), 1936-1987; Mayer, Robert R.
- Allocation of staff time and FAPs to direct charitable activities (Reports 008832), 1971 (Box 371)
  Memorandum to Vice Presidents, Heads and POICS.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Officials and employees; Bell, David E., 1919-; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Pending tax legislation affecting the Foundation's activities (Reports 008833), 1969 (Box 371)
  Memorandum to overseas representatives.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Finance; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Law and legislation; Bell, David E., 1919-; Ford Foundation. Office of the Vice President
- Pending tax legislation affecting the Foundation's activities (Chapter 2) (Reports 008834), 1969 (Box 371)
  Memorandum to Overseas Representatives.
- Special guidelines on the legal framework for grants to foreign organizations (Reports 008835), 1973 (Box 371)
  Memorandum to Executive Officers, POICS and Heads, Administrative and Program Officers, and Overseas Representatives.
  Office of the Secretary and General Counsel
  Grants to foreign organizations; Legal framework -- Grants to foreign organizations; Dressner, Howard R.
- Revised special guidelines on the legal framework for grants to foreign organizations (Reports 008836), 1974 (Box 371)
  Memorandum to Executive Officers, POICS and Heads, Program and Administrative Officers, Assistant Administrative Officers, and Overseas Representatives.
  Office of the Secretary and General Counsel/International Division
  Grants to foreign organizations; Legal framework -- Grants to foreign organizations; Bell, David E., 1919-; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Farm forestry in north-west India: lessons from the 1980's (Reports 008837), 1990 (Box 371, Reel R-9302)
  Studies in sustainable forest management;4
  Agroforestry -- India; Eucalyptus -- India; Saxena, N. C., 1942-
- Indochinese refugees and the Ford Foundation: a report based on interviews with public and private agencies in New York and Washington, July 9-13 (Reports 008838), 1979 (Box 371)
  Indochinese refugees and the Ford Foundation; Refugees, Indochinese; Geithner, Peter F.
- Discussions with human rights groups in Europe (Reports 008839), 1976 (Box 371)
  Human rights advocates -- Europe; Bell, David E., 1919-; Ford Foundation. International Division
- International Human Rights Documentation and Reference Service: working group meeting London, June 22, 1979 other comments and an assessment of progress to date (Reports 008840) (Box 371)
  Memorandum to Francis X. Sutton, dated July 9, 1979.
  Human rights -- International coOperation; Heaps, David; International Human Rights Documentation and Reference Service.
- Gaps in research on transnational enterprises (Reports 008841), 1977 (Box 371)
  International business enterprises -- Research priorities; Research priorities -- Multinational corporations; Sauvant, Karl P.
- Research priorities concerning multinational firms and foreign direct investment: the economic issues (Reports 008842), 1977 (Box 371, Reel R-9302)
  International business enterprises -- Research priorities; Research priorities -- Multinational corporations; Hawkins, Robert G.
- Gaps of research in transnational corporations (Reports 008843), 1977 (Box 371)
  International business enterprises -- Research priorities; Research priorities -- Multinational corporations; Dunning, John H.
- First Organizational Meeting and Conference Caribbean Studies Association (Reports 008844), 1975 (Box 371)
  File memo, dated February 21, 1975.
  Ethnic groups -- Research -- Caribbean Area; Gardner, James A., 1943-; Caribbean Studies Association
- Program on the future of the international economic order (Reports 008845), 1976 (Box 371)
  Memorandum to the International Committee of the Board of Trustees, dated February 20, 1976.
  7 p. + appendices: tables -- 28 cm.
  International economic relations; Monetary policy -- International cooperation; Goodwin, Craufurd D. W.; Ford Foundation. Europe and International Affairs
- The Educational Opportunity Bank: The feasibility of a pilot project at the graduate level (Reports 008846), 1970 (Box 371)
  Student loan funds; Ashenfelter, Orley, 1942-; Educational Opportunity Bank
- Core proposal for Cleveland: evaluation (Reports 008847), 1967 (Box 371)
  Memorandum to S.M. Miller.
  13 p. + appendix.
  Cleveland proposal -- Core; Cunningham, J. V. (James Vincent), 1911-1985; Congress of Racial Equality CORE, Cleveland proposal.
- The International Division in Latin-America, 1980-1990, September 1980. (Reports 008848) (Box 371)
  Technical assistance -- Latin America; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Botero, Rodrigo; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- The social challenge to modern Islamic architecture: The Aga Khan Award for Architecture in the Spirit of Islam (Reports 008849), 1980 (Box 371)
  Lecture given on Islamic architecture.
  Architecture, Islamic; Soedjatmoko, 1922-1989
- The Ford Foundation's role in India's developing agriculture: a review of current and prospective activities in support of intensified agricultural development (Reports 008850), 1968 (Box 371)
  Briefing document to the recent visit by David E. Bell and Eugene Staples.
  Agriculture -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Philanthropy -- India; New Delhi Field Office Staff.; Ford Foundation India
- Visit to Beirut (Reports 008851), 1972 (Box 372)
  Memorandum to Courtney Nelson.
  Beirut visit; Harrison, Gordon A.; National Council on Scientific Research Grant proposal evaluation
- Report on European discussions (Reports 008852), 1972 (Box 372)
  Memorandum to David Freeman.
  OECD and Ford Foundation -- Energy Policy Project; Ames, Edward A.; Energy Policy Project OECD staff briefing.
- Center for Study and Development of Culture and the Arts (CENECA) (Reports 008853), 1984 (Box 372)
  Theater -- Chile; Performing arts -- Chile; Cultural property -- Protection; Fadul, Anamaria; Centro de Indagación y Expresión Cultural y Artística (Santiago, Chile)
- Report on the Centre for the Study of Developing Societies (Reports 008854), 1984 (Box 372)
  Research institutes -- Evaluation; Learned institutions and societies -- Evaluation; Social sciences -- Research -- India; Social scientists -- Training of -- India; Pye, Lucian W., 1921-2008; Centre for the Study of Developing Societies
- An assessment of the Vera Institute of Justice for the Ford Foundation (Reports 008855), 1984 (Box 372)
  06600329
  Vera Institute of Justice
  General support for Vera's research and demonstration projects in the field of criminal justice and the underclass.
  [iii], 69 p. -- 28 cm.
  Criminal justice, Administration of -- Research -- New York (N.Y.); Criminal Justice, Administration of -- United States; Crime prevention -- New York (N.Y.); Crime prevention -- United States; Grinker, William J.; Walker, Gary A.; Ford Foundation. Human Rights and Governance; Vera Institute of Justice
- The Ford Foundation's Latin American and Caribbean Program (Reports 008856), 1984 (Box 372)
  Developing Countries Program/Latin America and the Caribbean
  104 p.
  Technical assistance -- Latin America; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Some principles and steps to guide transition in the public service of Pakistan (Reports 008857), 1974 (Box 372)
  A report prepared for the Pakistan Administrative Staff College. --T.p.
  07450250
  Administrative Staff College
  Provide services of two consultants to assist the Staff College.
  17 p.-- 28 cm.
  Public service employment -- Pakistan; Civil service -- Pakistan; Career development -- Pakistan; Vocational guidance -- Pakistan; Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Stahl, O. Glenn (Oscar Glenn), 1910-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific; Administrative Staff College of India
- Post project review of the Information and Advisory Centre and training programmes in the Export Promotion Bureau, Government of Pakistan (Reports 008858), 1972 (Box 372)
  Export controls -- Pakistan; Foreign trade regulation -- Pakistan; Stanley, Alexander O.
- Follow-up survey of Ford Foundation's former grant recipients (Indonesia 1950-1980): a survey report prepared for the Ford Foundation (Reports 008859), 1983 (Box 372)
  Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation; Sukamto, Adriana Elisabeth, 1963-; Theisen, Gary
- Toward a new consciousness of America: field report: June 4-June 8 (Reports 008860), 1973 (Box 372)
  Pueblo Indians -- New Mexico; Indians of North America -- New Mexico; Blumenstiel, Alexander; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- A renewed Foundation program vis a vis Cuba (Reports 008861), 1978 (Box 372)
  Memo to James Himes, dated August 9, 1978.
  Political science -- Cuba; International relations; Human rights; Schuman, Barry; Ford Foundation
- The Community Development Corporation: strategy for integration, growth and coherence (Reports 008862), 1977 (Box 372)
  Community development corporations; Community development; Kravitz, Sanford L.; Oppenheimer-Nicolau, Siobhan
- Ford Foundation social engineering programs (Reports 008863), 1976 (Box 372)
  Social engineering programs -- Ford Foundation; Community development programs -- Ford Foundation; Public welfare -- Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation
- Hispanics: issues, problems, and opportunities in the United States (Reports 008864), 1984 (Box 372)
  Hispanic Americans--Social conditions; Minorities -- United States -- Social conditions; Ford Foundation. Human Rights and Governance
- Leaf-hoppers of rice fields in East Pakistan (Reports 008865), 1969 (Box 372)
  Rice -- Disease and pest resistance -- Bangladesh; Rice -- Diseases and pests -- Bangladesh; Entomology -- Research -- Bangladesh; Ishihara, Tomoo, 1923-
- Rice pests, diseases, and varietal resistance trials in East Pakistan (Reports 008866), 1971 (Box 372)
  06600125
  52 p. + appendices
  Rice -- Disease and pest resistance -- Bangladesh; Rice -- Diseases and pests -- Bangladesh; Rice -- Research -- Bangladesh; Lippold, Paul C.; International Rice Research Institute
- The East Pakistan Educational Equipment Development Bureau (Reports 008867), 1970 (Box 372)
  Education -- Bangladesh; Education and state -- Bangladesh; Melton, Reginald F., 1934-
- Kenya meeting for representatives, comment on agenda paper. Session IV, June 7, 1968, Resource bases for development (Reports 008868) (Box 372)
  L68-161.
  PAPER Conference (1968 June 6-8: Nairobi, Kenya)
  Development; Staples, Eugene S.; International Division
- Observations and recommendations re "Nigerian Institute of Management and Administration" (Reports 008869), 1963 (Box 372)
  Nigerian Institute of Management
  6 p. + appendix -- 28 cm.
  Executives -- Training of -- Nigeria; Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria; Hoslett, Schuyler Dean, 1918-; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; Nigerian Institute of Management
- Visit to Ibadan and Ife, August 2-4 (Reports 008870), 1973 (Box 372)
  07200456
  Family planning training program for nurses and physicians at the University's medical facility.
  Birth control -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Nigeria; Obstetrics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Nigeria; Gynecology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Nigeria; Universities and colleges -- Nigeria; Education, Higher -- Nigeria; Ward, Haskell G.; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; University of Ibadan
- Workshop on Needed Research in East Africa in Family Planning, Medical Research and Programme Trials, July 23-25: A brief report (Reports 008871), 1970 (Box 372)
  Brief summary of the workshop.
  07090496
  Birth control -- Africa, East; Armar, A. A.
- Planning a basic science curriculum for the Comprehensive Secondary School at Aiyetoro Western Nigeria (Reports 008872), 1974 (Box 372)
  A companion to the two volumes of General Science for Form I and Form II for the Comprehensive Secondary School. --T.p.
  Establishment of a comparative education center at the University in Nigeria.
  17 p. --- 28 cm.
  Science -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria -- Curricula; Curriculum planning -- Nigeria; Technical education -- Nigeria; Education, Secondary -- Nigeria; Watson, Fletcher G. (Fletcher Guard); Roberts, Douglas A. (Douglas Alan); Ford Foundation. Vice President; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa; University of Lagos
- Nigerian Institute of Management: "Development plans" (Reports 008873), 1972 (Box 372)
  Background information on and recommendations fro the Institute.
  Nigerian Institute Of Management
  79p. + appendices.
  Management -- Nigeria; Hutchison, T. A. M.; Nigerian Institute of Management; Nigerian Institute of Management; Urwick International Ltd.
- Discussions with Professor Olayide on future Foundation support for Department of Agricultural Economics at the University of Ibadan (Reports 008874), 1977 (Box 373)
  07100454
  Staff development fellowships and visiting faculty to expand and upgrade the University's Faculty of Agriculture
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Nigeria; Universities and colleges -- Nigeria; Education, Higher -- Nigeria; Biggs, Tyler, 1942-; Rockefeller Foundation; Ford Foundation
- Second Vocational Improvement Centres Seminar: seminar report (Reports 008875), 1973 (Box 373)
  "[Notes from] seminar held at the Bagauda Lake Hotel, Kano, 13th to 17th August, 1973, as part of the Vocational Improvement Centres Follow-up Programme." --T.p.
  07300443
  Kaduna Polytechnic
  Support for a vocational technical education program.
  68 p. -- 28 cm.
  Vocational Improvement Centres Seminar (2nd: 1973, Kano, Nigeria)
  Vocational education -- Nigeria -- Congresses; Technical education -- Nigeria -- Congresses; Technical institutes -- Nigeria; Vocational teachers -- Training of -- Nigeria; Teachers -- Training of -- Nigeria; Gardner, William; Hamper, William A.; Vocational Improvement Centres Seminar (2nd: 1973, Kano, Nigeria); Vocational Improvement Centres --Follow-up Programme
- Visit to West Africa-Sahel branch of Pan-African Institute for Development, Ouagadougou (Reports 008876), 1979 (Box 373)
  File memo dated January 25, 1979.
  07100536
  Pan African Institute For Development
  Support to strengthen the Institute's research capacity and to assist in the creation of a project support office.
  Rural development -- Africa, West; Community development -- Africa, West; McKee, Katharine; Pan African Institute for Development
- Visit to Pan-African Institute for Development, Yacunde (Reports 008877), 1978 (Box 373)
  Economic development; McKee, Katharine; Pan African Institute for Development
- Vocational Education Program for Nigeria (Reports 008878), 1964 (Box 373)
  Vocational education -- Nigeria; Skapski, Adam S.
- Universidad Metropolitana (Reports 008879), 1972 (Box 373)
  This is a report about the new Universidad Metropolitana in Caracas. It is based on information obtained during a visit to the University from November 29 to December 2, 1971.
  Education, Higher -- Venezuela; Banks, Robert, 1922-; Universidad Metropolitana (Caracas, Venezuela)
- A confidential report on the status and potential of archaeological science in India: University of Minnesota (Reports 008880), 1983 (Box 373)
  Archaeology -- India; Rapp, George Robert, 1930-
- Archaeological science in India: Status, potential and recommendations: University of Minnesota (Reports 008881), 1983 (Box 373)
- Planning for Universidad de Monterrey (Reports 008882), 1971 (Box 373)
  74 p. + appendices
  Universities and colleges -- Mexico; Aguilar-Hernandez, Alfonso; Academic Administrative Internship Program; Universidad de Monterrey
- The development of the Nigerian Institute of Management (Reports 008883), 1972 (Box 373)
  Education and consultancy -- Nigeria; Hutchison, T. A. M.; Nigerian Institute of Management
- Report on the Second Conference of the Association of African Universities (Reports 008884), 1969 (Box 373)
  Universities and colleges -- Africa -- Congresses; University cooperation -- Africa; Daly, Mason G.; Association of African Universities
- Handing-over notes on hte Nigerian Summer Science Institutes (Reports 008885), 1975 (Box 373)
  Establishment of a Comparative Education Center at the University in Nigeria.
  11 leaves -- 28 cm
  Science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Nigeria -- Curricula; College teachers -- Training of -- Nigeria; Education, Higher -- Nigeria; Kimball, Merritt E.; University of Lagos. Comparative Education Study and Adaptation Centre
- End of tour report by the team of Nigerian Biology educators which visited selected N.S.F. summer institutes for Biology teachers in the U.S.A. in (Reports 008886), 1973 (Box 373)
  Biology -- Study and teaching -- United States; Comparative education; Eluwa, Mark C., Dr.; Aderinlewo, 'Dele
- Notes on discussion pertaining to technical education in Lagos, 16-26 (Reports 008887), 1972 (Box 373)
  Technical education -- Nigeria; Teachers -- Training of -- Nigeria; Education, Higher -- Nigeria; Comparative education; Fox, Melvin J.; University of Lagos. Comparative Education Study and Adaptation Centre
- Irrigation Management Meeting, Washington, November 4-5, 1982: minutes. (Reports 008888) (Box 373)
  Water -- Management; Irrigation
- Studies in national unity in West African countries (Reports 008889), 1971 (Box 373)
  Nationalism -- Africa, West; Political science -- Africa, West; Political sociology; Smock, David R.
- Language curriculum for Nigeria (Reports 008890), undated (Box 373)
  Language -- Study and teaching -- Nigeria; Education--Nigeria; Shaplin, Marjorie L.; Yoruba Primary Project
- Survey of selected Brazilian libraries and documentation centers: report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 008891), 1974 (Box 373)
  Library science -- Brazil; Libraries -- Brazil; Kahler, Mary Ellis
- The Foundation in Lebanon: (Reports 008892), 1976 (Box 373)
  Political science -- Lebanon; Administrative agencies -- Lebanon -- Finance; Endowments -- Lebanon -- Evaluation; Edwards, Robert H.; Ford Foundation
- Foundation experience in Iran and Turkey (Reports 008893), 1979 (Box 373)
  Endowments -- Iran -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Turkey -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management; Ward, F. Champion, 1910-2007; Ford Foundation
- Visit to Riyadh (Reports 008894), 1974 (Box 373)
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Egypt; International economic relations; Nelson, Courtney; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Report on Robert College and the American College for Girls, Istanbul, Turkey (Reports 008895), 1957 (Box 373)
  34 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Education, Higher -- Turkey; Education, Humanistic -- Turkey; Universities and colleges -- Turkey -- Finance; Educational assistance -- Turkey; Endowments -- Turkey -- Evaluation; Davidson, Carter, 1905-1965; Dodd, Paul A.; Robert College (Istanbul, Turkey); American College for Girls (Istanbul, Turkey)
- Comments on agenda paper: Session V, languages and linguistics (Reports 008896), 1968 (Box 373)
  L68-161
  Languages and linguistics; Fraenkel, Peter; International Division
- Overseas Development Program evaluation (1951-1961) and statement of current objectives and policies (Reports 008897) (Box 373)
  This report provides an overview of grantmaking activities from 1951 to 1961 in South and Southeast Asia, Latin America and Caribbean, and the Near East and Africa including a list of successful and unsuccessful projects for each region.
  Overseas Division/Latin America;Overseas Division/South and Southeast Asia;Overseas Division/Near East and Africa
  Economic development -- Developing Countries; Rural development -- Developing countries; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Education -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development
- A review of the problem of personnel for Overseas Development: progress report (Reports 008898), 1962 (Box 373)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management; Endowments -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Notes on the world's food problem (Reports 008899), 1966 (Box 373)
  Food supply -- Developing Countries; Agricultural productivity -- Developing countries; Hill, F. F. (Forrest Frank), 1900-
- Prospective development needs overseas and the evolution of Ford Foundation's OD Overseas Development Program (Reports 008900), 1966 (Box 373)
  Charity organization -- Developing countries; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Ward, F. Champion, 1910-2007; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- International Division Meeting, Beirut: summary notes (Reports 008901), 1967 (Box 373)